Guide to the Stanford University, Program in American Studies, records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Program in American Studies, records
1970-2008
SC1198
4.5 Linear feet
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Collection Contents
- Records
  - Results of 2000 Review and Report, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - American Studies Review 1989, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - American Studies Review 1984-85, 1983-1985 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - AS Review 1995, 1989-1995 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - American Studies [Review], 1995-2001 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Review of Major [American Studies], 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Program in American Studies Newsletter, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - American Studies 171 (P.S. 183F) "The Development of American Law", 1979-1983 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - AMSTUD 201 Spr 97-98, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - AS 202 99-00, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Core seminar: American Studies 202 The Shaping of 20th-Century America, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Beyond Ethnicity Consent and Descent in American Culture, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - The Politics of Riot Commissions 1917-1970, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Core Seminar: Amer. studies 201 The South Since 1880, 1983-1990 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Am. St. 203/English 186A American Autobiography - Fliegelman, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - American Studies 204/History 252 Museums and History, 1989-1994 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Am Stud 205 Labor, Race, Politics in the Industrializing West, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - AS 206 Win 02-03, 2002-2003 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - AS 207 Spr 04 Am Workers, Intl Politics and Global Capitalism, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Core Seminar: American Studies 206 The Automobile and American Culture, 1984-1985, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Core Seminar: American Studies 207 Technology in American Society, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Intro to American Indian Literature Eng 187K/AS 210, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Am St 212/Hist 271 - Fredrickson Ideas in American from the Revolution to 1900, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - AMSTUD 215 Weiner Spr 97-98 Multiculturalism in American Law, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - American Studies 215 Medicine and Culture in America, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - AmStud 216 Major Trials Weiner Win 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Am. St. 179 "Law" 1st Course Reader, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - A.S. 179 Introduction to American Law, 1985-1990 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Core Seminar: American Studies 221 Technology and American Culture, 1983-1992 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Core Seminar: American Studies 219 Major Interpretations of American History: The Age of Consensus, 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Core Seminar: American Studies 220 Photographs as Historical Documents [also 1994-1995 AMSTUD 200 Perspectives on American Identity], 1983-1989 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - A.S. 233 Asian Americans and Immigration Policy, 1992-1995 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Am. St. 240 - Research Seminar, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Other American Studies Seminar, 1975-1993 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - American Studies 150 Archives - "American Literature and Cultures to 1865", 1978-1988 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Amer. Stud. 152/ Hist 152 Archives - "Introductionto Material Culture", 1989-1991 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Amer. Studies 151 / Hist 103A Archives - "Transformation of American Thought", 1987-1989 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Core Seminar: Am Stud 214 Archives: The American 1960s, 1986-1991 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - AS Majors Flyer, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - American Studies Newsletter, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Am Stud Syllabi, 1992-1995 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - AS Study Honors College, 2002-2003 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Am St Review - Brady Committee, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - A.S. 37, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - A.S. 35 - the 1950s, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - American Studies 36, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - AS 50 (Student Initiated) - Prison-Industrial Complex, 2001-2002 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - American Studies 59 - Basic Criminal Law, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - American Studies 115 - Corn, 1995-2002 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - AmStud 124 - Education and Equality in Am Culture - Dermott, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - AS 125 - California Culture - Corn, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - American Studies 100 (Eng 128/Hist 174) - "Reflections on the American Condition", 1980 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - American Studies 131 - Philipino History - Cabezas, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - AS 130 - Philipino American History, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - AS 151 - Gillam, 1991-2004 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - 158 - Cases in Controv. Rakove, 2002-2003 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - American Studies 160 - Peter Carroll - American Culture Through American Film, 1977-1986 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Materials for Review Committee, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Faculty Seminar, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - AS Student / Faculty Dinners Archives, 1986-1993 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Archives - Early American Studies Proposals - Coe Professorship, 1944-1957 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Fundraising, 1974-1977 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - AS Grad Survey, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - AS Newsletter, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - AS Newsletter, 2000-2004 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - AS Newsletter, 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Archives - Proposal for the A.B. in American Studies, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Interdisciplinary Program Review, 2000-2001 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - HHP Review - Curriculum Committe, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - HHP Review - Course Listings from 1997 Review, 2000-2001 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - HHP Review, 2001-2001 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Interdisciplinary Studies in Humanities - Program Review, 2006-2007 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - American Studies Newsletter, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - ID HUM, 2000-2006 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Interdisciplinary Studies in Humanities - Program Review and Sample Programs, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - GPH Reform Review, 2008-2009 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Humanities Review, 2008-2009 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - American Studies Stanford History, 1953-1970 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Archives Scrapbook, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - AS Major - History, 1986-1994 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Hum 323: Ren/Early Mod, 2002-2007 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Senior Essays - Humanities, 1947-1984 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - 334A Modern Tradition, 2002-2003 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - MTL 360 - Marsh, 1989-1994 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - MTL 361, 1999-2002 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - MTL Welcome Dinner, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - MTL 261B/361B Colloquium, 1997-1998 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 361- The Modern Tradition, 1992-1998 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Modern Thought 364 - Thinking Lit and Politics, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - MTL 395 - The New Geography, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - 836 Psychiatry and Literature - John van Natta, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - MT6 125 - Weisberg - Intro to Modernism and Post-Modernism, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - MTL 150 - Video Editing, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Comp Lit 165 - How Practical are Lit Theories, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Van Natta (John) Classes, 1989-1991 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Modern Thought and Literature 293, 1989-1991 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - GPH (Graduate Program in Humanities) Book LIst, 2003-2004 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Hum 90 - Sophomore Course Archives, 1981-1997 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Interim, 1999-2001 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - GPH Archives, 1985-2001 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - MTL, 1995-1998 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - MTL, 1999-2000 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - MTL 199 ABC Cultural Studies, 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - MTL 195 Race and Racism, 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - MTL 190B (Heredia), 1996-2003 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - MTL 190W Humanism (Weinsfone) Spring 00-01, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - MTL 191 Topics in Amer Comic Perf Win 97-98, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - MTL 192 Human Technology Rel--Weinstone Spr 97-98, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - MTL 193 Stein Thomas, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - MTL 212 Spr 96-97, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Modern Thought 214 Van Natta, 1993-1999 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - MTL 225 Race in Am Law Winter 95-96, 1995-1996 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - MTL 238 Jurisprudence Stacy Spr 01-02, 2001-2002 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - MTL/CompLit 239 Legal Studies Philo and Lit Spr 00-01, 2000-2001 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - MTl 257 Law and Culture, 1995-1999 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - 322 Medieval, 1999-2008 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - GPH 324 Enlightenment, 2002-2006 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Hum 325 Modern (J Sheehan), 2002-2008 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - AS Committee, 2004-2006 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Graduate Program in Humanities Curriculum Archives Hum 301, 302, 303, 304, 305, 306, 1984-1989 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - GPS 321 Classical Sen, 2002-2003 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Honors Core Colloquium, 1998-2006 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - GPH Syllabi, 1992-1998 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - GPH Booklists 201-306, 1984-1992 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Hum MA Handbook, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - GPH Brochure, 1992-2002 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - MTL Review (Old), 1988-1995 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - 1994 MTL Review, 1989-1995 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Modern Thought and Literature History File, 1970-1977 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - FAC Senate, 1993-2000 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - MTL Review 1999, 1999-2000 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Post Review Matters, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - 2003 Review, 2003-2004 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - MTL Reading Lists Official, 1977-1979 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - MTL Newsletter Past History, 1970-1986 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Ruch, Alexander L, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Shelley in Asia, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 35)